Southwest Folklore Center Field Recordings Collection 1943-ongoing
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Southwest Folklore Center Field Recordings Collection, 1943-ongoing
SWF 011
Southwest Folklore Center
Reel tape recordings produced by University of Arizona Folklore Committee from 1943 through 1978, and after 1979, by the Southwest Folklore Center. Predominately field recordings from southern Arizona, they include cowboy songs and music, oral history interviews and corridos. The collection also includes 12 studio master tape reels recorded by Mexican American singer Lydia Mendoza.
70 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
Restricted. Users are required to use preservation cassette copies of the tape reels when available. An item level listing of all tape reels in the collection is available.
Historical Note
The University of Arizona Folklore Committee, founded in 1943 by Frances Gillmor, collected songs, tales and general folklore from all parts of the state. Upon its dissolution in 1979 the Southwest Folklore Center was created and continued its activities of collecting folklore material in the field in Arizona, the Southwest, and northern Mexico. The field collection topics varied by interests and needs of the community as well as changes in the nature of folklore collecting. Major field collecting on reel-to-reel tapes was done in the areas of cowboy songs and poetry, and Tucson history.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Series I: Audio Recordings, 1943-ongoing
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes dubbed versions of selections from the Center’s Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection as well as field recordings of the University of Arizona Folklore Committee. These include regional music such as Mormon hymns, cowboy songs, Mexican American music and corridos, Native American music, and fiddle and banjo tunes. Recorded interviews concern family life and traditions, home remedies, Native American languages, Tucson slang, and oral histories.
During 1974 and 1975, James S. Griffith collected field recordings while working for the Smithsonian Institution Office of Folk Life. Contributions of field recordings were made to the Bicentennial Festival of American Folk Life held in Washington, D.C., in 1976. The collection includes original copies of these tapes.
Recordings made after 1980 were collected by James S. Griffith in southern Arizona, and relate chiefly to cowboy music and songs, corridos, oral history interviews about Tucson history and family life, and the annual Wa:k Powwow All O'Odham Fiddle Orchestra Contest.
Mendoza, Lydia.; Mexican Americans -- Music.; Corridos.; Pioneers.; Frontier and pioneer life.; Yaqui Indians.; Navajo Indians.; Seri Indians.; Apache Indians.; Yuma Indians.; Hopi Indians.; Tohono O'Odham Indians.; Pima Indians.; Mormons--Arizona--Music.; Cowboys.; Cowboys--Songs and music.; Folklore.; Folklore--Arizona.; Mormons--Arizona--Folklore.; Cowboys--Arizona--Folklore.; Cowboys' writings, American.; Ranchers--Arizona.; Fiddle tunes.; Baptists.; Hobo songs.; Harmonica music.; Gospel music.; Bluegrass music.; Banjo music.; Navajo code talkers.; Arizona--Tucson.; Arizona--Phoenix.; Arizona--Patagonia.; Arizona--San Carlos.; Mexico.; Arizona--Camp Verde.; Arizona--Prescott.; Arizona--Salt River.; Arizona--Globe.; Arizona--Benson.; Arizona--Showlow.; Arizona--Florence.; Arizona--Tolleson.; Arizona--Safford.; Arizona--St. John's.; Arizona--Pinetop.; Arizona--Sedona.; Arizona--Clay Springs.; Arizona--Casa Grande.; Arizona--Skull Valley.; Arizona--Payson.; Arizona--Wheatfield.; Arizona--Bowie.; Arizona--Chino Valley.; Mission San Xavier del Bac (Tucson, Ariz.); Arizona--Rillito.; Arizona--Miami.; Arizona--Chinle Valley.; Arizona--Black Canyon City.; Arizona--Cottonwood.; Arizona--Springerville.; Arizona--Mayer.; New Mexico--Gallup.
Container List
- Audio Recordings, 1943-ongoing; Series I
  Items are arranged according to accession into the collection. Descriptive information about each item appears with each item.
  - Harriet Emeline Phelps, Pioneer days in Mesa, Ariz., May 18, 1966; Customs... holidays... medicine... celebrations... Christmas gifts and decorations... Mormon celebration... birthdays... marriage... children's games... clothing in pioneer days... making soap... travel... swimming customs... Indian washing woman... Transcribed Sept. 6, 1966. Transcript available in SWF 013, box 15, folder under Burnette or Phelps. Collected by Douglas Burnette in Mesa, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-395)
  - Hazel Harrow, Papago [i.e. Tohono O'Odham] Indian tribe customs, May 25, 1967; Childhood in Southern Arizona... Farming methods... foods and cooking... drying peaches... folk remedies... childhood games... tribal folktales... responsibility of old people... green corn tamale... cactus fruit... loco weed... Transcribed May 25, 1967. Collected by Byrd Granger in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-396)
  - Emilia Hernandez de Alvarado, Fiestas in Mexico, 1961; Fiestas in Mexico, particularly in Minatitlan, Vera Cruz... mother of Renato Rosaldo, University of Arizona faculty member... Transcribed... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Gillmor. Collected by Frances Gillmor in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-397)
  - Mrs. Morris and others, Men of Hoteville, Indian customs and music, Mexican songs, undated; Men of Hoteville... Hopi Buffalo dance song... Butterfly dance song... Hopi version of Navajo buffalo dance song... Song of mixed dance Kachinas... Hopi longhair dance song... Closing away song... You are going far away -- Death has 'proached him too -- The old hen flew over the yardy -- Game of Parlez-vous -- Betty and Charley -- Billy boy -- Nice young Mormons... Corridos... Untitled songs in Spanish... work songs... song to wake workers... Mormon gospel song.... Collected by Vicente Acosta, Charles Wiley, Mrs. John A. Ray, Peter Tufts, Doris Seibold in Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-398)
  - Uplegger, undated; This is a phonetic tape and cannot be transcribed...Uplegger is handwritten on back of box. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-399)
  - Marguerite Collier, History of Las Posadas at Carrillo School, Tucson, November 27, 1965; Childhood... formation of Carrillo School Folklore Club... Eddy Jacobs... Zopita Castro... letters to soldiers WWII... Las Posadas... Piñata party... Tucson Festival Society... Transcribed Aug. 16, 1966... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 4, under Collier. Collected by Frances Gillmore and Anne Lawrence in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-400)
  - H.B. Aguirre, Freighting from Wilcox to Globe, undated; Freighting on railroad... Stage coaches... Indian conflicts... Supplying beef to Silverbell Mine... San Jose Mission... El Tejano story... Transcribed... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Elias. Collected by Aravella Elias in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-401)
  - Anna H. Fortune, Folk medicine, July 23, 1961; Neighbors around their ranch in 1892... Feedler, Goud, Parks, Watkins, Sheehy families... Mules bringing materials to the mines... Names of mines... Old Patagonia... School in Harshaw, Ariz... Crittendon, Ariz... School teaching in Calabasas, Tubac, Bisbee... Transcribed Oct. 8, 1966... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 6, under Van Valkenburg. Collected by Anna H. Fortune in Patagonia, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-402)
  - Margaret Morales, Pima folk medicine, June 1962; Pima folk medicine... Medicine man... Curing animals... Evil spirits... Home remedies... Ceremony of curing... Coyote's superstitions... Indian sicknesses... Forbidden foods... Collected by Loretta Herbert in Phoenix, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-403)
  - Joe Stevens and son, Lee Stevens, San Carlos Apache medicine men, April 17, 1955; San Carlos Apache medicine men... Indians belief in medicine... Going to the medicine man... The Sings... Cure for lightning victim... Beginning of snake dance... Transcribed Aug. 19, 1966... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Kellner. Collected by Larry Kellner in San Carlos, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-404)
  - Joe Stevens and Lee Stevens, San Carlos Apache medicine men, April 17, 1955; Bad signs... Indians and politics... Devil dancers and horses... Medicine women... Puberty rites... Evolution of language... Transcribed Aug. 19, 1966... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Kellner. Collected by Larry Kellner in San Carlos, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-405)
  - Gustavo Terrazas, Yaqui folk medicine in Mexico, July 1964; Yaqui folk medicine in Mexico... cures learned by oral history... remedies classified by temperature... Numerology... Use of charms... Collected by Frances Gillmor in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-406)
  - Harvey Hance and Posie, Folk history around Camp Verde and Prescott, Arizona, October 13, 1965; Brands, branding irons and rings... Cattle... Cattlemen: Miller and the Monroes... Sheep invasion... Three H brand... Freight stations and cattle drives... A day working cattle... Cattle business in Texas... Tombstone, Ariz... Hunting... School in Camp Verde... The Hance Ranch... Roads in Arizona... Cowboys... The chuck wagon... Horseshoe and Agua Fria Ranch... Prescott, Ariz... Neighbors... Goddard Station... Cienega Station... Transcribed Jun. 10, 1966... Transcript available in MS 340, box 7, folder 6. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-407)
  - M.J. Young, Stories of Arizona, Utah, and Wyoming, Summer 1964; Trip to Yuma... Fortuna, Ariz... Rules of the road for hobos... Al Draper, drunken saloon keeper... Mary Murphy's boarding house... Copper mining... Sheep herding in Echo Canyon... Calamity Jane... Transcribed Sept. 13, 1973... Transcript available in SWF 013, boxes 15 and 16, under Young or Wilson. Collected by John and Mertena Wilson in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-408)
  - M.J. Young, Stories of Arizona, Utah, and Wyoming, Summer 1964; Mining methods, hard rock mining... Mormon miners... Company mining stores... Importance of candles... Glory hole, a mine... Fortuna, Ariz... Saloons in the town... Mules in mining... Transcribed July 23, 1974... Transcript available in SWF 013, boxes 15 and 16, under Young or Wilson. Collected by John and Mertena Wilson in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-409)
  - Sally Pemberton, Livingston and Roosevelt areas in early days, undated; About the Livingston and Roosevelt areas in the early days... Travels... Roosevelt... Indians in the area... Al Sieber, Apache Scout... Windy Hill and Grapevine... Arizona George... Marin Ranch... Globe, Ariz... Salt River...Neighbors... Social life and dances...Transcribed Jul. 26, 1974... Transcript available in SWF 013, box 15, under Van Valenburg or Pemberton. Collected by Sally Van Valenburg in Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-410)
  - Mrs. DeGracia, A. L. Richards, and others, Folklore, undated; Side 1: Story about El Tejano... Jose Lamurieta... The Ballad and tale of El Merino... San Xavier del Bac... The miracle cure of San Francisco... El Rebozo... Stories of lost mines... Ghost stories... Marriage customs in Mexico... La Llorona... Death superstitions of Colima region... Collected by Aravella Elias in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-411)
  - Jim Griffin, Cowboy songs, undated; Side 2: Cowboy songs... Your mother still prays for Jack -- Cowboy Jack -- I'll be hanged -- War song -- Careless love -- Wayfaring strangers -- Motherless child -- Barbara Allen -- Green grows the lilacs -- Black hills -- Marching to Pretoria -- Delia -- Hillbilly heaven -- Round the floor -- Mistletoe bough -- Streets of Laredo... Collected by Ben E. Timian in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-412)
  - Sallie Pemberton, History of Globe, San Carlos area, undated; Description of San Carlos area... 1887 travel to Arizona... Cooking for canal crew... Al Sieber... Windy Hill and Grapevine... Livingstone... Black settlement near Camp Verde... Arizona George... Neighbors... Salt River... Transcribed Sept. 13, 1973... Transcript available in SWF 013, box 15, under Van Valenburg or Pemberton. Collected by Sally Van Valenburg in Globe, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-413)
  - Frank Wilder Jordan, Folk history of Sentinel, Ariz. and other place names, February 8, 1958; Bat Cave... King Woolsey... Mail contract from Sentinel to the Haraquahala Mine... Description of the Fortuna Mine... Judge Silent... Oatman Mountains... 4th of July Wash... Yellow Medicine Wash... Loudermilk Wash... Oatman Canyon... Route to Phoenix from Oatman Flat... Agua Caliente... Transcribed Sept. 1966... Transcript available in MS 340, box 7, folder 6 OR in SWF 013, box 15, under Jordan or Granger. Collected by Byrd Granger in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-414)
  - Frank Wilder Jordan, Folk history of Oatman Flat and Arizona place names, February 8, 1958; Massacre of Oatman family... Andrew Stark... Creed Bryant... Stage station at Oatman Flat... Transcribed Sept. 1966... Side 2 is backwards... Transcript available in MS 340, box 7, folder 6 OR in SWF 013, box 15, under Jordan or Granger. Collected by Byrd Granger in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-415)
  - Charles U. Pickrell, Oral history, March 1969; Cattle ranching... Livestock... Supplies and cooking... Personalities... Tack and horses... Beef... Stories... Changes in cattle business... Submitted by Mrs. Charles Pickrell... Transcript available in SWF 013, box 16, under Pickrell or Granger. Collected in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-416)
  - Isabel D. Elias, History of family, friends and about Mexico, February 7, 1959; Don Perfecto and buried treasure... The Elias family during Gadsen Purchase... Early Tucson... Geronimo... Cananea... San Juan's Day... Transcribed 1959... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Elias. Collected by Aravella Elias in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-417)
  - M.J. Young, Stories of Arizona, Utah and Wyoming, Summer 1964; Railroad stories... Polygamy... Silver King and Ontario Mine... Lost Dutchman Mine... Turkey Bill... Whiskey man... Transcribed Jul. 19, 1974... Transcript available in SWF 013, boxes 15 and 16, under Young or Wilson. Collected by John and Merta Wilson in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-418)
  - William R. Ridgeway, Gila County folklore, January 18, 1964; Indian attacks... Outlaw "Chicon"... Mormon Robert Edge... Power brothers... Transcribed Aug. 9, 1974... Transcript available in SWF 013, box 16, under Ridgeway or Deckter. Collected by Larry Deckter in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-419)
  - Luisa Ramon, Folk songs in Spanish and English, December 12, 1950; Includes Corridas... Civil War song... Corrido de Cananea... Cowboy's lament... Song about Zapata and the Revolution... Collected by Vicenta Acosta in Patagonia, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-420)
  - Gail Gardner, Songs written by Gail Gardner, March 30, 1958; Tyin’ knots in the devil's tail -- The Moonshine steer -- The Dude wrangler -- Old cowhand -- He drowned Romie behind the millpond -- Going back to Arizona -- Cowboy for a lifetime -- Sierry Petes -- Collected by Ben E. Timian in Prescott, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-421)
  - Yaqui Indians, Dance and ceremony, later folk songs, December 24, 1958; Ceremony with dance, music, songs. Collected by Frances Gillmore in Yaqui Village, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-422)
  - Mrs. Pickrell, Remembrances, November 26, 1968; Early married life... Arizona towns and mines... Forest and mineral conservation... Stories... Politicians... Charles Pickrell... Collected by Byrd Granger. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-423)
  - Roberto Thompson, Seri Indian beliefs and tales, November 29, 1969; Recorded at Seri Indian Village... In Spanish... Mysticism... Spirits... Fasting and journey to sacred caves... Tales of little doll people... Song in Seri language... Food and agricultural cycle... Sea and river system... Tales - Coyote - Iguana... Collected by Nancy Holbert in Desemboque, Sonora, Mexico. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-424)
  - Laverne Clark, Navajo and Apache mythology about horses, undated; Mrs. Clark wrote They sang for horses... Navajo and Apache concept of mythical horse... Deities and ceremonies... Medicine rites of Navajo concerning horses... Navajo song for good horses... Acquisition of horses in myth and reality... Why the white man got the horse... Horse fetishes... Apache painting of yellow mare... Transcript available in SWF 013, box 15, under Clark or Granger. Collected by Byrd Granger in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-425)
  - Charles Pickrell, Westerners speech, March 1969; Pickrell's background... Mormon religion... Becker family of Prescott... Diet of early settlers... Stories about Roxy Donaldson, Jim Johnson, John Hamps and others... Collected by E. H. Brunners in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-426)
  - Jane Edith Paradise Miles, Early experiences in Arizona, February 11, 1969; Easter celebration... Wayward girls... County hospital... Fruit sellers and rag pickers... Childhood games... Entertainment... July 4th celebrations... Holidays... Small pox... Transcript available in SWF 013, box 16, under Miles or Granger. Collected by Byrd Granger in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-427, R-428>)
  - Gladys Barker and Alfred Whiting, Havasupai morning song, Granny Pemberton, folk songs and fiddle music, March 1950; Mohave mourning song... Havasupai peach song... Navajo Indian love song... Bonaparte's retreat... Wait for the wagon... Silvery Colorado... Streets of Laredo... and more... Collected by Vicente Acosta, Charles Wiley, Mrs. John A. Ray, Peter Tufts, and Doris Seibold in Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-429)
  - Bonaventure Oblasser, Christmas Mass at San Xavier Mission, undated; Recording of Christmas Mass at San Xavier Mission, Bonaventure officiating... Papago [i.e. Tohono O’Odham] Festival... Collected in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-429)
  - Odd S. Halseath, Chants, songs, dances from various Indian tribes of the Southwest, 1954; An explanation for the history of Indian chants and a short explanation for each song included... Cochiti Pueblo: Chaquenna... Travel song... Cradle song... Daybreak song... Green corn dance... War chant sung... War chant for safe return of soldiers, 1944... Other: Eagle in the air... Narrow eagle... Bluebird chant... Medicine prayer... Antelope chant... Mother earth song... Feather dance song... Bosque Redondo song... Squaw dance songs... Zuni corn dance... Jemez arrow dance... Kiowa round dance... Kiowa war dance... Taos round dance... Pima Kingfisher song... Cocopa Karuk... Apache Gahan... Comanche peyote song... Seneca face song... Collected by Odd S. Halseath in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-429)
  - Yuma Indian dances, folk songs, and grade school chorus, undated; Yuman chants... Cocopah chant... Gahan Apache chants... Comanche Peyote song... Drinking song... Wilcox to Globe folk song... Soldier and a Maid... My grandfather's farm... The sheriff's sale... Nice young Mormon... Old and only in the way... Mormon song... Medicine man and snake ceremony... Mormon plays... Collected by Vicente Acosta, Charles Wiley, Mrs. John A. Ray, Peter Tufts, and Doris Seibold in Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-429)
  - Yaqui Indians, Yaqui music during Christmas Eve festival, December 24, 1958; Song with fiddle... Explanation and song (vocal)... Song with fiddle and rattles (instrumental)... Song by chorus... Fiddle, rattles and chorus... Collected by Frances Gillmor in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-429)
  - Eula Holland, Oral history project - Early pioneers of Tucson, Ariz., May 22, 1974-August 13, 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Eula Holland, early pioneer of Tucson, Ariz... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 1. Collected by Byrd Granger and M. Davis in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Souter, Oral history project, May 23, 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interviews with Mr. and Mrs. Souter, early pioneers of Tucson, Ariz... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 2. Collected by Byrd Granger and M. Davis in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Amparo Carrillo, Oral history project, February 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Amparo Carrillo, early pioneer of Tucson, Ariz... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 1. Collected by Byrd Granger and Kathy Kessler in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Candelaria Lopez, Oral history project, February 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Candelaria Lopez, early pioneer of Tucson, Ariz... In Spanish... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 2. Collected by Byrd Granger and Alva Torres in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Vicente Palomino, Oral history project, May 28, 1974-June 11, 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Vicente Palomino, early pioneer of Tucson, Ariz... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 2. Collected by Byrd Grander and Gloria Chester in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Elena Sayre, Oral history project, June 19, 1974-June 25, 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Elena Sayre, early pioneer of Tucson, Arizona. Collected by Byrd Granger and M. Davis in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Ethel Tolley, Oral history project, June 25, 1974-August 1, 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Ethel Tolley, early pioneer of Tucson, Ariz... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 2. Collected by Byrd Granger and M. Davis in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Vicente Alfaro, Oral history project, undated; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Vincente Alfaro, early pioneer of Tucson, Arizona. Collected by Byrd Granger and Gloria Chester in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Ida Celaya, Oral history project, undated; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Ida Celaya, early pioneer of Tucson, Ariz... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 1. Collected by Byrd Granger and Gloria Chester in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Mrs. Del Moral, Oral history project, May 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Mrs. Del Moral, early pioneer of Tucson, Ariz... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 1. Collected by Byrd Granger and Gloria Chester in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Mrs. Claunch, Oral history project, May 21, 1974-June 20, 1974; Oral history project for the City of Tucson... Interview with Mrs. Claunch, early pioneer of Tucson, Ariz... Transcript available in MS 340, box 6, folder 1. Collected by Byrd Granger and M. Davis in Tucson, Arizona. (Box SWF Pre-1980,, Folder R-430)
  - Everett Brisendine, Brisendine Interview: Poetry reading, November 5, 1975; Tape contains interview and poems: Self introduction poem -- Arizona -- To a wonderful lady -- In memory of [Prud?] -- Untitled poem about not giving up... Transcript available in 80-2/R.1.T... Collected by James S. Griffith in Chinle Valley, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 3 3/4 ips, 5 in. (Box 80.2, Folder R.1)